<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sahar Design</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 22:21:52 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 22:21:52 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Best Online Courses</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love to learn new skills! Whether it’s for my professional life or personal, I’m always looking for ways to improve. How about you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m assuming yes, because you’ve navigated to this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As designers, our field is always changing. Yet instead of taking night classes at a local college or University, we can rely on the Internet to help update our skill sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully there’s a plethora of online courses available and at any price point. You can easily become a Photoshop pro or earn a certificate in social media online. The options are endless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally learn better by watching videos, and if you are like me, you’ll find the resources below helpful. They’ve definitely helped me throughout the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my top 6 favourite online learning tools and courses you can use to help further your expertise. Best part, you can learn at your pace and track your progress. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;01-lyndacom&quot;&gt;01. LYNDA.COM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/learning_lynda.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynda.com founded by Lynda Weinman is one of the most popular websites for online training and offers a wide variety of high-quality courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a Lynda.com subscriber for over 10 years and I check out a topic every few weeks. I joined their website when they only had a handful of subjects. Now you can find tutorials on most subjects through their site. They also have an amazing selection of influencer interviews that I’m a big fan of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynda.com was recently acquired by LinkedIn. If you have a LinkedIn account you can now connect the two and have your completed courses show up on your LinkedIn profile as lynda.com certificates. This can be a plus if you are looking for a job 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more at lynda.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;02treehouse&quot;&gt;02.TREEHOUSE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/learning_threehouse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treehouse is more focused on web and mobile development than other desktop applications. Through their courses you’ll be able to learn about HTML, CSS, WordPress, and iOS platforms for app development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have over 1000 videos created by expert teachers on web design, coding and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treehouse breaks courses down into easy-to-digest chunks with quizzes and mini-challenges which are fun to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more at teamtreehouse.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;03-skillshare&quot;&gt;03. SKILLSHARE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/learning_skillshare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skillshare is a learning community for creators. Anyone can take an online class, watch video lessons, create projects, and even teach a class themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite courses on Skillshare is Lettering for Designers: One Drop Cap Letterform at a Time by Jessica Hische a San Francisco based illustrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more at skillshare.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;04-udemy&quot;&gt;04. UDEMY&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/learning_udemy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Udemy has a massive and varied catalog of self-paced online courses, many of which are free. It enables professionals to share or sell their expertise through courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Udemy courses are divided into sections and lectures. Lectures can be video micro-lectures, but they can also include audio, text, and presentation slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite course on Udemy is Seth Godin’s Freelancer course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more at udemy.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;05the-creative-class&quot;&gt;05.THE CREATIVE CLASS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/learning_creativeclass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Creative Class by Paul Jarvis is an online business course for freelancers to help get more clients, better pay for designers, developers, writers and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to find a good course like The Creative Class. Learning the business side of things through this course will prove to be invaluable in your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Paul’s style of teaching, since he gives examples from his personal experiences. It’s nice to learn from an entrepreneur who has over 20 years of experience as a freelancer and who also understands the design side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you sign up for his course you’ll also get access to a Slack channel where you can connect with hundreds of other freelancers to chat, brainstorm, talk pricing and get feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more at creativeclass.io&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;06-b-school&quot;&gt;06. B-SCHOOL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/learning_bschool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B-School by Marie Forleo is an 8 week, interactive video-based training program that teaches smart, effective online marketing strategies to business owners who want more sales and more impact from their online presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to grow your business, this course is a must! It has proven to be very helpful in growing my personal business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;marieforleo.com/bschool&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 15:50:03 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/04/06/best-online-courses.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/04/06/best-online-courses.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HOW TO CREATE AN EFFECTIVE STYLE GUIDE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most important aspects in having a successful brand is consistency.
A consistent brand makes the visual aspects easily identified, and creates trust between your business and your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One easy way to maintain visual consistency is by creating a style guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A style guide is a document that outlines the specific logos, colors, typography, imagery, etc. of your company’s brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having worked with different agencies for many years, I have come across many different style guides, and I’ve seen some that are over 100 pages, and some that are as short as a single sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be a big brand to make use of the style guide benefits. Even as a small startup or a one person business, creating this document can help you with your online presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every brand style guide will need different information depending on how complex your brand may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listed below are few basic elements that most likely can appear on every visual guide. And to help you have a better understanding, I have included samples of the style guide I created for our company Strutta plus few examples from other brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;01-logo&quot;&gt;01. LOGO&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your logo is a key element of your brand, and in order to stay consistent along the way your guide needs to define exactly how it should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create at least 2 versions of the logo: one for light and one for dark background&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define space between the Logotype and other elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specify the minimum size for your logo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beware how not to use the logo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_logo1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_logo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_logo3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;02-color&quot;&gt;02. COLOR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since colors can be easily shifted from designer to designer or application to application, make sure to specify the values to the point so you don’t end up with a color that clashes with your original design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give exact RGB color code as well as CMYK and Pantone for print use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include a set of secondary colors along with the primary ones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick neutral colors (white, grey and black) so your primary brand colors can stand out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use sites such as LOLcolors, Adobe Color for inspiration and creating sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_color1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_color2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_color3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;03-typography&quot;&gt;03. TYPOGRAPHY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every brand should have a consistent set of fonts. Listing out these fonts, with examples and character sets, is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stick to 2 or 3 fonts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specify sizes for elements such as headings, sub headings and body text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose weights and font styles within a font family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_type1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_type2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;04-imagery&quot;&gt;04. IMAGERY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your images reflect your brand just as much as your graphic elements, logo, fonts and colors and can help you set your brand apart from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specify a photographic style for your brand (bright, high contract, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define how and where photos should be used within your brand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose a subject line for your photos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create your style around the photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_imagery2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/post_styleguide_imagery3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you find the above tips helpful to create your own style guide. It’s essential to begin with what is most necessary for you and take it from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to realize that brands evolve over time. The style guide you create today might be different than the one you’re using in a year. So its good practice to version your guides with date and always keep the old versions so you can refer back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please share your comments blow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 15:47:03 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/design/2016/04/06/how-to-create-an-effective-style-guide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/design/2016/04/06/how-to-create-an-effective-style-guide.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
